RG 005:026, Office of the Governor: Wilbur L. Cross (1931-1939)
Connecticut State Library
- Series 2. Subject Files, 1931-1939; T001169
  - 1935-1937
    - Fort Griswold and Groton Monument Commission (Box 395)
    - General Assembly (Box 395)
    - General Assembly - Committee Hearings on Bills (Box 395)
    - General Assembly - Messages to (Box 395)
    - General Assembly - Special Session, 1935 (Box 395)
    - General Assembly - Special Session, 1936 (Box 395)
    - Geological and Natural History Survey Commission (Box 395)
    - Governors Conference, 1935 (Box 395)
    - Governors Conference, 1936 (Box 395)
    - Governors Conference, 1937 (Box 395)
    - Hairdressers and Cosmeticians (Box 395)
    - Harbormasters (Box 395)
    - Hartford Industrial Athletic League (Box 395)
    - Hartford Tercentenary Commission (Box 395)
    - Harvard Tercentenary Celebration (Box 395)
    - Healing Arts, Board of (Box 395)
    - Health Department (Box 395)
    - Highway Department (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Beaumont Highway (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Green Mountain Highway (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Hattertown Road (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Hotchkiss School and Ore Hill (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Lloyd Plains Road, Weston (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Merritt Parkway (Box 396)
    - Highway Department - Woodstock Road (Box 396)
    - Homeopathic Medical Examining Board (Box 396)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar (Box 396)
    - Housatonic River Conservation Committee (Box 396)
    - Household Employment Study (Box 396)
    - Housing Act (Box 396)
    - Housing Administration, Federal (Box 396)
    - Housing Project, Bridgeport (Box 396)
    - Inaugural Ball (Box 396)
    - Independence Day (Box 396)
    - Insurance Department (Box 396)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 396)
    - Interstate Compacts (Box 396)
    - Invitations Accepted (Box 396)
    - Invitations Regretted (Box 396)
    - Italian Celebration [Conquest of Ethiopia] (Box 397)
    - Jail Farm (Box 397)
    - Jails, County (Box 397)
    - Jewish New Year Greeting (Box 397)
    - Judgeships (Box 397)
    - Judicial Council (Box 397)
    - Labor Department (Box 397)
    - Liquor Control Commission (Box 397)
    - Long Lane Farm (Box 397)
    - Maloney, Francis T. (Box 397)
    - Mansfield Training School (Box 397)
    - Manufacturers Association of Conn. (Box 397)
    - Marsh Brothers (Box 397)
    - Mediation and Arbitration Board (Box 397)
    - Medical Examining Board (Box 397)
    - Memorandums to Gov. Cross (Box 397)
    - Mental Diseases, Commission on (Box 397)
    - Meriden School for Boys (Box 397)
    - Metropolitan District Commission (Box 397)
    - Middletown State Hospital (Box 397)
    - Military (Box 397)
    - Milk Administrator (Box 397)
    - Milk Control (Box 397)
    - Motor Vehicle Dept. (Box 397)
    - Mystic Oral School for the Deaf (Box 397)
    - National Emergency Council (Box 397)
    - National Exhibition of American Art (Box 397)
    - National Legislation (Box 397)
    - National Textile Act (Box 398)
    - Naturopathic Examiners (Box 398)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute - Dr. Burlingame (Box 398)
    - New England Railroad Commission (Box 398)
    - New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad (Box 398)
    - Newington Home (Box 398)
    - Norwich State Hospital (Box 398)
    - Notary Public (Box 398)
    - Nurses, Board of Examiners and Registration (Box 398)
    - Opticians, Commission (Box 398)
    - Optometric Society (Box 398)
    - Pardons, Board of, 4 folders (Box 398)
    - Park and Forest Commission (Box 398)
    - Paupers Laws, Commission to Study (Box 398)
    - "Penny Letters" (Box 398)
    - Pharmacy Commission (Box 398)
    - Phillips, Alfred N., Jr., Mayor of Stamford (Box 398)
    - Policemen, Special (Box 398)
    - Potato Act of 1935 (Box 398)
    - Press Matters (Box 398)
    - Prevailing Rate of Wage Board (Box 398)
    - Proclamations (Box 398)
    - Psi Upsilon (Box 398)
    - Public Utilities Commission (Box 398)
    - Public Utilities, Commission to Investigate (Box 398)
    - Public Welfare Council (Box 398)
    - Public Welfare Department (Box 398)
    - Public Works Administration (Box 398)
    - Publicity Commission (Box 399)
    - Purple Heart, Military Order of (Box 399)
    - Putnam Park Commission (Box 399)
    - Red Cross (Box 399)
    - Reformatory, Cheshire (Box 399)
    - Rehabilitation Corporation (Box 399)
    - Remington Rand, Inc. Strike - New York Office (Box 399)
    - Reorganization Commission (Box 399)
    - Reorganization Commission - Minutes of Meetings (Box 399)
    - Republican State Platform, 1936 (Box 399)
    - Requisitions (Box 399)
    - Resignations (Box 399)
    - Rhode Island - Connecticut Boundary Line (Box 399)
    - Rhode Island tercentenary (Box 399)
    - Rivers, Harbors and Bridges Commission (Box 399)
    - Rogers, Will - Memorial Commission (Box 399)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Appeals to (Box 399)
    - Roosevelt, F.D., Trip through Connecticut (Box 399)
    - Salvation Army - Major Miller (Box 399)
    - Sculpture Commission (Box 399)
    - Secretary of State (Box 399)
    - Shellfish Commission (Box 399)
    - Sherwood Island State Park (Box 399)
    - Smith, J. Francis (Box 399)
    - Social Security Act (Box 399)
    - State Agencies and Institutions (Box 399)
    - State Employment Service - Advisory Council (Box 399)
    - State Farm for Women (Box 399)
    - State Library (Box 399)
    - State Planning Board (Box 399)
    - State Police Department (Box 399)
    - State Teachers' Association - F.E. Harrington (Box 399)
    - State's Attorney, 1935 (Box 399)
    - Street and Highway Safety Commission (Box 400)
    - Supreme Court (Box 400)
    - Tax Department (Box 400)
    - Tercentenary Celebration, 1935 (Box 400)
    - Texas Centennial (Box 400)
    - Transient Program (Box 400)
    - Treasury Department (Box 400)
    - Tuberculosis Commission (Box 400)
    - Unemployment Insurance Commission (Box 400)
    - Uniform State Laws, Commission of (Box 400)
    - Veterans Home Commission (Box 401)
    - Veterinary Examining Commission (Box 401)
    - Water Commission (Box 401)
    - Waterway Compact Commission (Box 401)
    - Welfare Commissioner (Box 401)
    - Wethersfield Prison (Box 401)
    - Whitfield House Project (Box 401)
    - Works Progress Administration (Box 401)
    - Wynne, Kenneth - Personal (Box 401)
    - Yale University (Box 401)
    - Youth Hostel Movement (Box 401)
  - 1937-1939
    - Accountancy, State Board of (Box 402)
    - Addresses (Box 402)
    - Aeronautics, Dept. of (Box 402)
    - Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 402)
    - Agriculture, Dept. of (Box 402)
    - American Legion (Box 402)
    - Antiquities, Conn. Association for the Preservation of (George Coffing Warner) (Box 402)
    - Architects, Board of Examiners of (Box 402)
    - Athletic Commission, State (Box 402)
    - Attorney General (Box 402)
    - Bank Commission (Box 402)
    - Bank Commission, Advisory Council (Box 402)
    - Barbers' Commission (Box 402)
    - Birthday Ball, President's, 1937 (Box 402)
    - Birthday Ball, President's, 1938-1939 (Box 402)
    - Bridgeport Housing (Box 402)
    - Chemists - State (Box 402)
    - Cheshire Academy (Box 402)
    - Child Labor Amendment (Box 402)
    - Chiropractic Examiners, State Board of (Box 402)
    - Civil Engineers, Board of (Box 402)
    - Clarence Ransom Edwards Commission (Box 402)
    - Clippings, Miscellaneous Newspaper (Box 402)
    - Common Pleas Court (Box 402)
    - Compensation Commissioner (Box 402)
    - Comptroller (Box 402)
    - Conn. College for Women (Box 402)
    - Conn. College for Women (Meeting, Bd. of Trustees) (Box 402)
    - Conn. College for Women (Report on Budget) (Box 402)
    - Conn. League of Municipalities (Box 402)
    - Conn. League of Voters (Box 402)
    - Conn. Prison Association (Box 402)
    - Conn. State College (Box 402)
    - Conn. State College (Minutes of Meetings) (Box 402)
    - Coordinator of Relief (Box 402)
    - Council of State Governments and American Legislators' Assoc[iation] (Box 403)
    - County Commissioners (Box 403)
    - Court System (Box 403)
    - Dairy and Food Commission (Box 403)
    - Deaf and Dumb Wards, Commission on the Care of (Box 403)
    - Dental Commissioner (Box 403)
    - Domestic Animals Commission (Box 403)
    - Eastern Connecticut Commission (Box 403)
    - Eastern States Exposition (Box 403)
    - Education, Dept. of (Box 403)
    - Education of the Blind, Board of (Box 403)
    - Embalmers, Examiners of (Box 403)
    - Emergency Relief Commission (Box 403)
    - Employment Service Advisory Council (Box 403)
    - Engineers and Land Surveyors, Board of Registration for Professional (Box 403)
    - Fairfield County Jail (Box 403)
    - Fairfield State Hospital (Box 403)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box 404)
    - Federal Writers' Project (Box 404)
    - Finance and Control (Box 404)
    - Finance and Control (Box 404)
    - Financial Adviser (Box 404)
    - Financial Responsibility Act, Commission to Study (Box 404)
    - Fisheries and Game (Box 404)
    - Fisheries and game, State Board of - Endorsements (Box 404)
    - Fitch's Home for Soldiers (Box 404)
    - Flood Control (Box 404)
    - Flood Control Commission (Box 404)
    - Flood Relief Fund (Box 404)
    - Forest and Park Association - Conn. (Box 404)
    - Forest and Park Commission (Box 404)
    - Fort Griswold and Groton Monument Commission (Box 404)
    - General Assembly, Messages to (Box 404)
    - General Assembly, Next (Box 404)
    - General Assembly - Topics 1937 Session (Box 405)
    - Geological and Natural Survey Com[mission] (Box 405)
    - Governor's Cabinet (Box 405)
    - Governor's Conference, 1937-1938 (Box 405)
    - Hairdressers and Cosmeticians (Box 405)
    - Harbormasters (Box 405)
    - Hartford County Jail (Box 405)
    - Hartford Junior College (Box 405)
    - Hartford Retreat (Box 405)
    - Healing Arts, Board of (Box 405)
    - Health Department (Box 405)
    - Highway Department (Box 405)
    - Homeopathic Medical Examination Board (Box 405)
    - Hospital Service Plan (Box 405)
    - Housing (Box 406)
    - Housing Act (Box 406)
    - Human Resources, Special Commission to Survey (Box 406)
    - Hurricane Flood (Box 406)
    - Inaugural Address (Box 406)
    - Inaugural Ball, 1937 (Box 406)
    - Insurance Department (Box 406)
    - Intergovernmental Cooperation, Commission on (Box 406)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 406)
    - Investment Committee (Box 406)
    - Invitations Accepted (Box 406)
    - Invitations Regretted (Box 407)
    - Israel Putnam Memorial Commission (Box 407)
    - Jails, County - Insane (Box 407)
    - Jails, Legislative Committee on (Box 407)
    - Jewish New Year, 1937 (Box 407)
    - Jewish Oppression (Box 407)
    - Judgeships (Box 407)
    - Juvenile Court (Box 407)
    - Labor Department (Box 407)
      - Truck Strike (Box 407)
      - Electric Boat (Groton Strike) (Box 407)
    - Legislative Council (Box 408)
    - Lieutenant Governor (Box 408)
    - Liquor Control Commission (Box 408)
    - Long Lane Farm (Box 408)
    - Mansfield Training School (Box 408)
    - Manufacturers Association of Conn. (Box 408)
    - Mediation and Arbitration, State Board of (Box 408)
    - Medical Examining Board (Box 408)
    - Memoranda (Box 408)
    - Mental Diseases Commission (Box 408)
    - Meriden School for Boys (Box 408)
    - Merritt Parkway (Box 408)
    - Metropolitan District Commission (Box 408)
    - Middlesex County Jail (Box 408)
    - Middletown Bridge (Box 408)
    - Military (Box 409)
    - Mild Administrator (Box 409)
    - Motor Vehicles (Box 409)
    - Mystic Oral School (Box 409)
    - National Exhibition of American Art, 1937 (Box 409)
    - National Legislation (Box 409)
    - Naturopathic Examiners (Box 409)
    - Naval Armory in New Haven, A Commission to inquire into the advisability of erecting (Box 409)
    - Nazi Camp, Southbury (Box 409)
    - New England Conference, 1938 November 17 (Box 409)
    - New England Council (Box 409)
    - New England Governors Conference (Box 410)
    - New Haven County Jail (Box 410)
    - New Haven Tercentenary (Box 410)
    - Newington Home (Box 410)
    - New York - Conn. Boundary Line (Box 410)
    - Norwich State Hospital (Box 410)
    - Nurses - Board of Examination and Registration (Box 410)
    - Old Age Assistance Commission (Box 410)
    - Opticians, Commission of (Box 410)
    - Optometry (Box 410)
    - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, State Board of (Box 410)
    - Pardons, Board of (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1937 February 1 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1937 May 1 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1937 November 1 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1937 December 10 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1938 March 19 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1938 May 2 (Box 410)
      - Meeting, 1938 November 7 (Box 410)
    - Pardons, Board of - Vacancy (Box 410)
    - Pauper Laws, Commission to Study (Box 410)
    - Pennsylvania State Commission (Box 410)
    - Pension Commission (Box 410)
    - Pequots, Commemorating Expedition Against the (Box 410)
    - Personnel Department (Box 411)
    - Policemen, Special (Box 411)
    - Pollution of Waterways, Commission to Formulate Treaty to Prevent (Box 411)
    - Proclamations (Box 411)
      - Thanksgiving Proclamations, 1937 (Box 411)
      - Thanksgiving Proclamations, 1938 (Box 411)
    - Publicity Commission (Box 411)
    - Public Utilities Commission (Box 411)
    - Public Welfare Council (Box 411)
    - Public Welfare Department (Box 411)
    - Public Works, State Department of (Box 411)
    - Purchases, Supervisor of (Box 411)
    - Reformatory - Cheshire (Box 411)
    - Regatta, Governor's (Box 411)
    - Regional Market (Box 411)
    - Rehabilitation Committee (Box 411)
    - Remington Rand [Strike] (Box 411)
    - Reorganization (Box 412)
    - Requisitions (Box 412)
    - Retirement Plan - State Employees (Box 412)
    - Rhode Island - Connecticut Boundary Line (Box 412)
    - Rivers, Harbors & Bridges Commission (Box 412)
    - Salvation Army (Box 412)
    - Saugatuck Valley (Box 412)
    - Sculpture Commission (Box 412)
    - Secretary of State (Box 412)
    - Sesquicentennial of U.S. Constitution (Judge Wynne) (Box 412)
    - Shellfish Commission (Box 412)
    - Sheriff (Box 412)
    - Sherwood Island State Park (Box 412)
    - Social Security (Box 412)
    - Soil Conservation Districts Law (Box 412)
    - Standardization Committee (Box 412)
    - State Bonds - Committee to Control the Issue of (Box 412)
    - State Farm for Women, Connecticut (Box 412)
    - State Library (Box 412)
    - State Planning Board (Box 412)
    - State Police (Box 413)
    - State's Attorney (Box 413)
    - Statute Revision Commissioner (Box 413)
    - Street and Highway Commission (Box 413)
    - Swedish Commission (Box 413)
    - Tax Dept. (Box 413)
    - Teachers' Retirement Board - State (Box 413)
    - Texas Co. New Tanker - Connecticut (Box 413)
    - Textile Freight Rates (Box 413)
    - Treasury Dept. (Box 413)
    - Tuberculosis Commission (Box 413)
    - Unemployment Compensation Act by Special Session, 1936 (Box 413)
    - Unemployment Compensation - Advisory Council (Box 413)
    - Unemployment Compensation Commissioners (Box 413)
    - Unemployment Compensation Commission (Box 413)
    - U.S. Congressmen (Box 413)
    - Vermont Chamber of Commerce (Box 413)
    - Veterans Home Commission (Box 413)
    - Veterinarian Examining Commission (Box 413)
    - Wage Rages - Board to Establish on Highways and Bridges (Box 413)
    - Water Commission (Box 413)
    - Waterway Compact Commission (Box 413)
    - S.S. Connecticut (Box 413a)
      Governor Cross's copy. Bound volume containing 46 mounted black and white photographs of the launching of the Texas Company tanker, S.S. Connecticut and ceremonies, circa September 1, 1938.
      See also file, "Texas Co. New Tanker - Connecticut" in Box 413.
      Formerly on open shelves.
    - Welfare Department Relief Plan, Special Committee to Prepare (Box 414)
    - Wethersfield Prison (Box 414)
    - Whitfield State Museum (Box 414)
    - Workmen's Compensation Commission (Box 414)
    - Works Progress Administration (Box 414)
    - World's Fair, 1939 (Box 414)
    - World's Fair Commission (Box 414)
    - Yale University (Box 414)
    - Youth Hostel Movement (Box 414)
    - Correspondence concerning appointments to offices as judge or county commissioner, 1937-1938 (Box 415)
      - County Commissioner (Box 415)
      - Supreme Court of Errors (Box 415)
      - Court of Common Pleas (Box 415)
      - Judgeships - town courts (Box 415)
      - Judges (Box 415)
- Series 3. Place cards, 1935 April 10; 1 item; 2002-020
  Shows political cartoons.
  In shared hollinger.